Guide to the Costume and Set Designs for the Stratford (Ontario) Shakespeare Festival:
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Costume and Set Designs for the Stratford (Ontario) Shakespeare Festival:
1956-2002.
Bernstein, Raphael, collector.
9 linear ft. (5 flat boxes, 5 framed items, and loose items).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
5767616
Biographical Note
Raphael Bernstein received his B.S. from Columbia University's School of Engineering in 1956 and his M.B.A. in 1959. The Parnassus Foundation was established in December 1986 by Raphael and Jane Bernstein for purposes that include the encouragement of original creative work in the arts and humanities.
The Shakespearean Stratford Festival was established in 1953. The festival is world renowned and takes place in four theatres throughout the city: the Festival Theatre, Avon Theatre, Tom Patterson Theatre and the Studio Theatre. Celebrities such as Alec Guinness, Christopher Plummer, and Dame Maggie Smith have performed at the festival.
Scope and Content
138 original scenic, costume, and prop designs, executed variously in watercolor, gouache, pastel, ink, colored pencil, and graphite pencil for the Stratford Shakespearean Festival or Canada, as well as some related items. Some of the designs have attached fabric swatches. The bulk of the work is designs for Shakespearean plays, but there are also designs for other works such as "The Man of La Mancha" and Gogol's "The Government Inspector."
In the collection there is a three-ringed binder of individually cataloged images, as well as a publication by the Hood Museum of Art, "Designs for theatre: Stratford Festival, 1954-1990 / Hood Museum of Art, in association with the Stratford Shakespearean Festival Foundation of Canada".
This collection is arranged by individual artists. The Call Number is from the three-ringed binder of individually cataloged images which is part of the collection.
Subjects
Stratford Festival (Ont.); Benson, Susan.; Brown, Lewis.; Clark, Patrick.; Curtis, Ann.; Hanson, Debra.; Heeley, Desmond.; Hurry, Leslie, 1909-; Mann, Martha.; Mitchell, Clare.; Moiseiwitsch, Tanya, 1914-; Paraschuk, Doublas; Paye, Robin Fraser.; Pennoyer, John.; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616--Stage history--Canada.; Silver, Philip.; Thorne, Gary Thomas.; Wallace, Victoria.; Costume design drawings.; Set design drawings.; Design drawings
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Raphael Bernstein Gift July 2006 2006-2007-M8
Purchased by Raphael Bernstein.
- Benson, Susan
  - Set Design for Stratford Festival's "Guys and Dolls," Gamblers, Act 1 and Act 2 (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.90.58)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "The Relapse," Goldie Semple as Berinthia (Box 7)
    (Call Number: TH.90.62)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "The Tempest," Dogs (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.35)
  - Costume design for "Guys and Dolls," Street Photographer and Man with Billboard (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.90.61)
  - Costume design for "Guys and Dolls," Alan Jordan as Nathan Detroit, Act 2, Scene 7 (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.90.60)
  - Set design for Stratford Festival's "Guys and Dolls," Policemen and Street People, Act 1 Scene 2 (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.90.59)
- Brown, Lewis
  - John Neville as Henry Higgins in "My Fair Lady," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.02.16)
- Clark, Patrick
  - Martha Burns as Regan from "King Lear" (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.95.5 or TH96.6 descriptions are identical)
  - William Hutt as Lear from "King Lear" (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.96.9)
  - Colombe Demers as Cordelia from "King Lear" (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.96.4)
  - Diane D'Aquila as Goneril from "King Lear" " (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.96.7)
  - Eric Donkin as Gloucester from "King Lear" " (Box 5)
  - Lady in Waiting from "Richard III" " (Box 5)
  - Jordan Petite as Fool from "King Lear" (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.96.12)
  - Martha Burns as Regan from "King Lear" " (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.97.29)
  - Robert King as Old Man from "King Lear" (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.96.11)
  - William Hutt as Lear from "King Lear" " (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.96.8/9)
  - Surrey and Norfolk from "Richard III" (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.97.30)
- Curtis, Ann
  - Richard Curnock as Sir Jasper Fidget in "The Country Wife" (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.02.18)
  - Colm Feore as Joseph Surface in "A School for Scandal" (Box 6)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Twelfth Night," Roberta Maxwell as Maria (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.91.37)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Twelfth Night," Albert Millaire as Malvolio (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.91.36)
  - Colombe Demers as Alexandra, Act II from "The Little Foxes" (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.96.24)
  - Colombe Demers as Alexandra from "The Little Foxes" (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.96.20)
  - Diana Leblanc as Birdie, Act II from "The Little Foxes" (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.96.22)
  - Martha Henry as Regina Hubbard from "The Little Foxes" (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.96.19)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Twelfth Night," William Dunlop as Sir Toby Belch (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.91.55)
  - Provisional Drawings from "The Little Foxes" (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.96.25)
  - Martha Henry as Regina in "The Little Foxes" (Box 5)
  - William Hutt as Ben, Act I, "The Little Foxes" (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.96.21)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Love for Love," Antoni Cimolino as Jeremy (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.90.63)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Love for Love," Brian Tree as Tripland (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.90.64)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Love for Love," Vickie Papers as Miss Prue (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.90.65)
- Dean, Charlotte
  - Julia as Sebastian from "Two Gentlemen of Verona" (Box 6)
    (TH.98.47)
- Hanson, Debra
  - Men of Inquisition from "Man of La Mancha" (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.98.35)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "As You Like It," Gary Crawford as M. LeGros (Box 7)
    (Call Number: TH.90.70)
  - Costume design for Stratford Festival's "Macbeth," Victor Young as Apparition King (Box 7)
    (Call Number: TH.90.88)
  - Lady Macbeth Sleepwalking (Box 7)
  - Apparition King 2 Tom MacDonald (Box 7)
  - Guards from "Man of La Mancha," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.34)
  - David Ludwig as Dr. Carasco from "Man of La Mancha," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: Th.98.32)
  - Larry Mannell as Barber from "Man of La Mancha," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: 98.31)
  - Gypsy Dancer from "Man of La Mancha," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: 98.36)
  - Gypsy from "Man of La Mancha," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: 98.37)
  - Mary Pitt as Maria--nightwear, from "Man of La Mancha," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: 98.33)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Hamlet," Peter Gaudreault as 3rd Player (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.91.41)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Hamlet," Sidonie Boll as Ophelia (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.91.38)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Hamlet," Mervyn Blake as the First Grave Digger (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.91.39)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Hamlet," Male Actors (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.94.23)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Hamlet," Sabrina Grdevich as Ophelia (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.94.24)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Romeo and Juliet," Antoni Cimolino as Romeo (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.44)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Romeo and Juliet," Bernard Hopkins as Friar Lawrence (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.43)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Romeo and Juliet," Megan Follows as Juliet (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.36)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Romeo and Juliet," Doria Martel as the Sun (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.37)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Romeo and Juliet," Antoni Cimolino as Romeo (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.39)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Romeo and Juliet," Antoni Cimolino as Romeo (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.38)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Romeo and Juliet," Paul Miller as Benvolio (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.41)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Romeo and Juliet," Michael Simpson as Peter (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.40)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Romeo and Juliet," Megan Follows as Juliet (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.42)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "As You Like It," Lucy Peacock as Rosalind (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.72)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "As You Like It," Lucy Peacock as Rosalind (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.71)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "As You Like It," David William as Jaques (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.89)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Hamlet," Rebels (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.91.19)
  - Set Design, Props, for Stratford Festival's "Macbeth," Witch's Altar (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.75)
  - Set Design, Props, for Stratford Festival's "Macbeth," Bishop's Crooks for Apparition King #1, 2 (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.73)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Macbeth," Macduff's Murderers (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.74)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Treasure Island," Michael Querin as Sam (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.91.51)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Treasure Island," Ron Hastings as George Merry (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.91.52)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Treasure Island," Brian Tree as Israel Hands (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.91.50)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "The Shoemaker's Holiday," Lord May or's Aldermen (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.66)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "The Shoemaker's Holiday," Lorne Kennedy as Hammon (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.68)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "The Shoemaker's Holiday," James Blendick as Simon Eyre (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH. 90.69)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "The Shoemaker's Holiday," Apprentices (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.67)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Hamlet," John Hampere as Ghost (Box 5)
    (Call Number: TH.91.40)
- Heeley, Desmond
  - "As You Like It" Stratford Ontario (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.02.19)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Amadeus," Kappelmeister (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.95.17)
  - Douglas Chamberlain as Merlin from "Camelot" (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.97.33)
  - Costume Design for the Metropolitan Opera's "Manon Lescault," for Miss Renata Scotto (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.95.6)
  - Stepsister No. 1 Dressing for the Ball, from "Cinderella," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.29)
  - Costume design for Stratford Festival's "Coriolanus," Len Carion as Titus and Soldiers (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.95.7)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "The Tempest," Ian Deakin as Ariel (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.95.8)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Amadeus," Salieri (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.95.15)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Amadeus," Magic Flute Audience (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.95.18)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "As You Like It," Le Beau (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.95.5)
  - Cynthia Dale as Guenevere from "Camelot" (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.97.31)
  - Tom McCamus as Arthur from "Camelot" (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.97.32)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "School for Wives," Ann Wright as Georgette (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.91.57)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "School for Wives," Albert Millacre as Chrysalde (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.91.53)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "School for Wives," Lewis Gordon as Oronte (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.91.56)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "School for Wives," Brian Bedford as Arnolphe (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.91.54)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "School for Wives," Colm Feore as Horace (Box 2)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "The Tempest," John Jarvis as Trinculo (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.95.9)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Phaedra," 2 Guards (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.78)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Phaedra," Roberta Maxwell as Ismene (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.77)
- Hurry, Leslie
  - Unidentified character from Julius Caesar (Box 7)
    (Call Number: TH.X.)
- Mann, Martha
  - Jeffrey Renn as Lepidus from "Julius Caesar" (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.38)
  - Robert Perschini as Cinna the Poet from "Julius Caesar" (Box 1)
    (Call Number:TH.98.40)
  - Senators from "Julius Caesar" (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.39)
- Mitchell, Clare
  - Duke of Cornwall from "King Lear," Stratford Festival of Canada 2002 (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.02.22)
  - Edmund from "King Lear," Stratford Festival of Canada 2002 (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.02.24)
  - Duke of Albany from "King Lear," Stratford Festival of Canada 2002 (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.02.21)
  - Kent in Disguise from "King Lear," Stratford Festival of Canada 2002 (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.02.23)
  - Lear from "King Lear," Stratford Festival of Canada 2002 (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.02.25)
- Moiseiwitsch, Tanya
  - Gratien Gelinas as Dr. Caius from "The Merry Wives of Windsor" (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.97.3)
  - Costume design for the Metropolitan Opera's "Peter Grimes," Fisherman (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.2)
  - Costume design for the Metropolitan Opera's "Peter Grimes," Sailors (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.4)
  - Costume design for the Metropolitan Opera's "Peter Grimes," Fisherman's Wife (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.3)
  - Costume Design from King Lear, Blakely as Kent (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.92.46)
  - Costume Design for the Metropolitan Opera Company's "Rigoletto," (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.45)
  - Costume Design for "The Government Inspector," B. Paul as Lyuluka (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.47)
- Paraschuk, Douglas
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "In the Ring," Janet Wright as Mado (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.94.25)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "In the Ring," Roland Hewgill as Coco (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.94.26)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "In the Ring," R. Hewgill and A. Renner as Ghosts (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.94.27)
- Paye, Robert Fraser
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Much Ado about Nothing" (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.91.43)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Much Ado about Nothing," Edward Atienza as Friaf Francis (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.91.42)
- Pennoyer, John
  - Cassie Fox as Amy from "Little Women" (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.97.12)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Our Town," Geoffrey Brumlik as Joe Crowell (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.91.44)
  - Douglas Rain as Thomas More from "A Man for All Seasons," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.46)
  - Diane D'Aquila as Alice from "A Man for All Seasons," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.45)
  - Kieth Diricol as Bishop Cramer from "A Man for All Seasons," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.44)
  - Joun Dobn as Thomas Cromwell from "A Man for All Seasons," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.43)
  - Diane D'Aquila as Alice from "A Man for All Seasons," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.41)
  - Attendant from "A Man for All Seasons," Stratford Festival (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.98.42)
  - Sean Astin Olson and Michael Shepherd as Marvilus and Flavius in "Julius Caesar," Festival Theater, Stratford Ontario (Box 1)
    (Call Number: Th.02.26)
  - Barbara Bryne as Aunt Marchfrom "Little Women," Stratford Festival (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.97.14)
  - Kristina Nicoll as Jo from "Little Women," Stratford Festival (Box 2)
  - Lewis Gordon as Old Mr. Lawrence from "Little Women," Stratford Festival (Box 2)
    (Call Number: TH.97.11)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Alice Through the Looking Glass," R.O'Driscoll as Goat (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.94.28)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Alice Through the Looking Glass," All the King's Men (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.94.29)
  - Costume Design from Stratford Festival's "Alice Through the Looking Glass," Chorus (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.94.30)
- Silver, Philip
  - Set Design for Stratford Festival's "Merchant of Venice," Act I, Scene I Street in Venice (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.96.13)
  - Set Design for Stratford Festival's "Merchant of Venice," Act II, Scene 5&6 Outside Shylock's House (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.96.14)
  - Set Design for Stratford Festival's "Merchant of Venice," Belmont Portico (Box 1)
    (Call Number: TH.96.15)
- Thorne, Gary Thomas
  - Set Design for Stratford Festival's "Knight of the Burning Pestle" Horseplay II (Box 6)
    (Call Number: TH.90.81)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Knight of the Burning Pestle," Antoni Cimolino as Humphrey (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.80)
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Knight of the Burning Pestle," Dwarf George (Box 4)
    (Call Number: TH.90.79)
- Unidentified
  - Unidentified (Box 1)
- Wallace, V.
  - Costume Design for Stratford Festival's "Knight of the Burning Pestle," Rankin as Pomponia (Box 3)
    (Call Number: TH.92.48)